Jacqueline Xu

Front End Developer

Contact

Email: xujacque@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/jqjacq

Website: https://jqjacq.github.io/

Located: New York/New Jersey

Summary

Versatile self-taught front-end developer with experience in multiple industries, such as education, hospitality, law, and administration. Proficient in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Committed to staying up-to-date with current technology, such as ChatGPT, continuous learning, and improvement in building responsive and user-friendly websites.

Skills

HTML	
CSS	••••
JavaScript	
React	
Bootstrap	••••
SASS	••••
Material UI	
Responsive Designs	
Microsoft Office	••••
NodeJS	
Git	

Education

City College of New York 02/2017 Bachelor of Arts in Psychology

Projects

Project# 1: E-commerce Website: JQ's Tea and Coffee

- Developed a e-commerce website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SASS, React, and MaterialUI
- Handle connecting data to components through props, maps, and routing.
- React state to change/update cover image, cart items, and store contact info.

Project #2: Dictionary Word Search

- Developed with Vanilla JavaScript to retrieve data from a public
 API
- Data is retrieved using mapping, forEach method, fetch, promise, and async-await.
- Error handling using try-catch.

Project #3: Habit Hamster

- Developing a web and mobile app for keeping track of habits with React and Material UI.
- Striving to make this project compatible with multiple platforms: websites, mobile, and smartwatches.
- Ongoing team project to create user experience design.

Work Experience

Customer Service Specialist, New York, NY *National Grid*

05/2019 - 08/2021

- Managed over 30-80 inbound customer calls per day efficiently, effectively, calmly, and courteously in a fast-paced call center environment.
- Verified customer information and processed payments, field orders, move-in, move-out, emergency service orders, disconnects/connects, agreements, meter changes, appointments, deposits, refunds, and reports that are monitored through the customer service management system and databases using the internal system: CRIS, CFE, and AIM.
- Resolved customer's billing complaints or discrepancies by analyzing bills, explaining bills, disputing investigations, issuing reimbursement, adjusting bills, rescheduling appointments, and reissuing bills

Teaching Coach & Office Manager, New York, NY 04/2019 – 03/2020 *Leap Education*

- Prepared, graded, and taught elementary students for the statewide test.
- Maintained and managed attendance, assigned works, and organized office functions for the first-graders to eighth-graders and distributed assignments to coaches

Administrative Coordinator, Tokyo, Japan

11/2017 - 12/2017

3Q Showa Guest House

Processed guest transactions and provided hospitality services such as housekeeping and maintaining the shared area.